<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
        <title>Benjamin L Albritton</title>
        <description>Benjamin L Albritton - Benjamin Albritton</description>
        <link>http://blalbrit.github.io</link>
        <atom:link href="http://blalbrit.github.io/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 09:39:57 -0700</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 09:39:57 -0700</pubDate>
        <ttl>60</ttl>


        <item>
                <title>DLCL122-2016 - Liz&#39;s Discussion Questions, Week 7</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;discussion-questions-week-7&quot;&gt;Discussion Questions, Week 7&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wednesday&quot;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What’s the interplay between spatial analysis and textual analysis? (the metadata analysis examples given in Tooling Up seem more like spatial analysis to me)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How quick to adopt has medeival studeis been in comparison to other areas of the humanities when it comes to “macroanalysis”?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/02/16/lizweek7questions</link>
                <guid>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/02/16/lizweek7questions</guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>DLCL122-2016 - Christina&#39;s Discussion Questions, Week 7</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;week-7-discussion-questions--christina-sampling--illustrating&quot;&gt;Week 7 discussion questions–Christina (Sampling &amp;amp; Illustrating)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.) If Voyant is an “environment,” how might one carry what is used from it into papers?  (i.e.: in order to take advantage of Voyant’s capabilites, do you really have to always be in the program itself—or what does it look like exported?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.) Is it true that Voyant &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; works with text? (copying and pasting text into a field–rather than Voyant being able to decipher a manuscript itself). This poses what challenges? Benefits?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/02/16/ChristinaWeek7DiscussionQuestions</link>
                <guid>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/02/16/ChristinaWeek7DiscussionQuestions</guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>DLCL122-2016 - Liz&#39;s Blog Post, Exercise 4</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;exercise-4-comparing&quot;&gt;Exercise 4: Comparing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this exercise, we were charged with the task of preparing two versions of a text for the Versioning Machine. The text I marked up was from a manuscript fragment of Rabanus Maurus’ “De rerum naturis”, which I previous transcribed in T-PEN. The second version of the text I used was an online edition which I used to assit my transcription. The turned out to be a mistake. Because I used the edition text to help expand the Latin abbreviations, and because the edition text was not at all abbreviated, the “differences” in the text were for the most part simply places where something had been abbreviated in the manuscript text. This is much less interesting than comparing two manuscript witnesses would be. So, I found the same fragment of text in a manuscript at the Parker library (CCCC MS 11) and transcribed &lt;em&gt;it&lt;/em&gt; in T-PEN, and finally adding a third witness to the TEI document for Versioning Machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;document-structure&quot;&gt;Document Structure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fragment is from book 2, chapters 1 and 2. I used these as the top two levels of organization for the TEI encoding. Getting a breakdown smaller than that was not so clear, as there are no “paragraphs” in the Stanford manuscript. There are, however, periodic red-filled capital letters. The Stanford manuscript is the one I care about most, so I chose the red letters as a way to further decompose the text despite it seeming arbitrary from the point of view of the other two witnesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;```xml&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div1 type=&quot;book&quot; n=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div2 type=&quot;chapter&quot; n=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
		&lt;p n=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
		&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p n=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
		&lt;/p&gt;
	
	&lt;div2 type=&quot;chapter&quot; n=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
	

```

### Defining Difference

As I first did the Stanford MS and the edition text before adding the second manuscript, the only differences in the texts were abbreviation, capitialization, and punctuation differences. In order to have differences to look at, I counted all three of these things as proper differences. When I added the second manuscript witness, it produced instances like this:

```xml
&lt;app&gt;
	&lt;rdg wit=&quot;#stanfordMS&quot;&gt; filius cham[.]&lt;/rdg&gt;
	&lt;rdg wit=&quot;#monumenta.ch&quot;&gt;, filius Cham,&lt;/rdg&gt;
	&lt;rdg wit=&quot;#parkerMS&quot;&gt;filius cham[.]&lt;/rdg&gt;
&lt;/app&gt;
```
To me, this seemed pretty uninteresting. The abbreviation differences in the manuscripts was the truly interesting piece. Differences in capitialization and punctuation occured fairly frequently, and were detracting from the abbreviation differences. For example:
```xml
&lt;app&gt;
	&lt;rdg wit=&quot;#stanfordMS&quot;&gt;iafeth dictus&lt;/rdg&gt;
	&lt;rdg wit=&quot;#monumenta.ch&quot;&gt;Iaphet dictus&lt;/rdg&gt;
	&lt;rdg wit=&quot;#parkerMS&quot;&gt;iapheth dict[us]&lt;/rdg&gt;
&lt;/app&gt;
```

Due to time constraints, I have not yest revised the document to reflect my new feelings on what constitutes a textual difference in this text. That&#39;s the other thing about TEI encoding-- it takes *forever* to do and, to the computer scientist in me, looks like something which cries out for automation.
&lt;/div2&gt;&lt;/div2&gt;&lt;/div1&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/02/14/lizblogpostE4</link>
                <guid>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/02/14/lizblogpostE4</guid>
                <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>DLCL122-2016 - Liz&#39;s Discussion Questions, Week 6</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;discussion-questions-week-6&quot;&gt;Discussion Questions, Week 6&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wednesday&quot;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What do we mean by “data”?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“The first Linked Data principle advocates using URI references to identify, not just Web documents and digital content, but also real world objects and abstract concepts… This principle can be seen as extending the scope of the Web from online resources to encompass any object or concept in the world.” This doesn’t seem even remotely possible as I understand it– what is going on here?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/02/09/lizweek6questions</link>
                <guid>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/02/09/lizweek6questions</guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>DLCL122-2016 - Christina&#39;s Discussion Questions, Week 6</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;week-6----discussion-questions&quot;&gt;Week 6 – Discussion questions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) How might we define “data”? Or, perhaps more productively, what does data not encompass?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(2) In the ‘conclusions’ section of this writing on ‘Linked Data,’ the author makes mention of major companies (Google, Yahoo, Facebook) who are “busy building such data spaces.” It says here that in contrast to the open Web–accessible to everyone–these “emerging data spaces are controlled by single companies which also decide how the data spaces are exploited.”  Isn’t this a bit worrisome?  What happens when certain companies have a ‘monopoly’ on information? (This may be a broad question, but it got me thinking about the limits of this…)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/02/09/ChristinaWeek6discussionquestions</link>
                <guid>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/02/09/ChristinaWeek6discussionquestions</guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>DLCL122-2016 - Christina&#39;s Discussion Questions, Week 5</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;week-5-discussion-questions&quot;&gt;Week 5 discussion questions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.) Does every major institution make their image avaliable via the IIIF image API? Your (Ben Albritton’s) post mentions that more and more institutions are supporting the IIIF image API. Just out of curiosity, which ones aren’t yet? What platforms other than Mirador are utilizing this IIIF image API, allowing for comparisons across manuscripts?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.) On the “A very gentle introduction to the TEI markup language,” there’s a discussion of preservation and creating standards for “scholarly memory in an evolving digital culture.”  Since I am a ‘newbie’ to all this, is it correct that TEI is mainly used by humanities scholars?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/02/03/csmith-week5discussion-questions</link>
                <guid>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/02/03/csmith-week5discussion questions</guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>DLCL122-2016 - Liz&#39;s Discussion Questions, Week 5</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;discussion-questions-week-5&quot;&gt;Discussion Questions, Week 5&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Monday
* What does it take for an institution to adpot IIIF? Are there economic considerations that might be slowing more adopting?
* Are there different versions of the TEI DTD? Do they vary significantly?
 * In the examples in the Introduction to TEI, I noticed they use a link to a dtd file that doesn’t exist anymore in the doctype declaration. Advantages and disadvantages of hotlinking…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wednesday&quot;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who generates the content of DigiPal?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How might IIIF (or a thing like it) work with tools that use polygons rather than rectangles?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;i.e. is there any value in selecting a polygonal region of an image? We’ve discussed non-rectangular selection in other areas… (though of course any non-rectangular image would secretly be living inside a transparent rectangle)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/31/lizdiscussionw5</link>
                <guid>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/31/lizdiscussionw5</guid>
                <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>DLCL122-2016 - Laney&#39;s Blog Post Annotations and Transcriptions</title>
                <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;blog-post-annotations-and-transcriptions&quot;&gt;Blog Post Annotations and Transcriptions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For annotating and transcribing, I selected science and medicine manuscripts because the content peaked my interest.  Once I identified them for inclusion in the Mirador instance for class, I panicked, worried that selecting manuscripts for this task based upon the content might have been a bad idea. Turns out the reason for my worries was because I didn’t think I would be able to make useful annotations or be able to transcribe the text because of my inexperience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;annotating&quot;&gt;Annotating&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I selected a Medical treatise from the 13th century because the text has three different scripts.  I started annotating with tags indicating the script.  The manuscript is a  bi-folio with two columns per page so I wasn’t sure how to indicate which column the selected text was in.  Then I was trying to figure out if it was worth indicating which column and/or side of the bi-folio for tagging.  I did not create any annotations because I’m still not sure exactly what I am looking at in the text.  I believe once I start transcribing the text, I may have some information to add as annotation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;transcribing&quot;&gt;Transcribing&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started looking at transcribing what I have indicated as script2 in the 13th century Medical treatise.  I selected this text because the font is bigger and easier to read.  However, my first attempt at transcribing was not successful.  I am finding that I still am looking at the text as I would an English language text.  It is going to take much more practice and help from others in the class to be able to complete the transcription.  Transcription is an art form and I have to remind myself that, like any new skill, it takes time to learn.  I was discouraged and my worries about not having Latin language skills surfaced along with my imposter syndrome.  But I will continue to work on improving my skills because I know I can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/26/laneymcg-BlogPost</link>
                <guid>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/26/laneymcg-BlogPost</guid>
                <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>DLCL122-2016 - Christina&#39;s Blog Post, Exercise 2</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Christina’s Blog post on, jointly, exercise 2 and exercise 3 (updated to reflect this)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In embarking upon exercise 2—which involved utilizing Mirador to digitally annotate folia held in Stanford’s online repository—I was initially skeptical of the program’s benefits.  Indeed, it impressed me that you could store annotations for others to use, reference, or edit in future, but other than that I was unsure about the merits of Mirador.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, after using it myself to begin digitally annotating the illuminated capitals of Stanford’s c.1450 Book of Hours and Psalter (with prayers ascribed to Saint Jerome and the Venerable Bede), my mind was changed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone trained in rigorous visual analysis—something instilled in me by countless medieval art historians—Mirador allowed me to look at the mis-en-page and iconographic program of a codex’s folio in a new light.  For example, as I spent a fair bit of time looking at folio 13 (the first digitized folio of the MS), I was struck anew thinking about what—and how—I wanted to annotate.  Mirador’s relatively easy-to-use user interface permitted me to engage with the illuminated capitals of this folio in a way I had never done before.  Its easy ‘tag’ feature made me think about how I would characterize certain decoration, letter size, and style.  I had never before had to think about making annotations consistent and understandable to a viewer other than myself—for that is how one would interact with my annotations normally, since I wouldn’t be able to explain them in person!  Added to this is the idea that, with Mirador (like many digital technologies), my annotations remain long after I’m ‘gone.’ (Or so they should!) This gives me the responsibility and task of making sure that my annotations are consistent and can be read, understood, and reused by a myriad audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, Mirador’s side-by-side comparative feature is wonderfully useful.  In fact, I wish every digital repository allowed one to do this! Viewing annotations for various folia within one manuscript, or across differing manuscripts, holds immense value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, one of the most difficult elements of trying to digitally annotate the illuminated capitals of this 1450 Book of Hours and Psalter was the fact that I didn’t know precisely how much information I should include.  At a certain point, tags (and even writing annotations within the text box) become no longer useful if there is simply &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; much information to wade through.  In this, the ‘bold’ text feature in the text box can be used to usefully pull apart key words and terms for the casual viewer, as they engage with an illuminated initial you’ve spent much time with.  (The ‘italic’ option for text has its own problems, probably a bug—for it doesn’t allow you to make text italic and instead hides the annotation frame altogether).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all, digitally annotating using the Mirador program made me rethink how I approach study of a medieval manuscript’s visual layout—down to its most basic level.  Digitally annotating on Mirador forces the annotator to make decisions about how they will categorize what they see so that it can be (hopefully) easily searchable and usable in contexts not just within a given manuscript…but also across manuscripts.  I look forward to using the Mirador tool a LOT more, not just in our projects for this class, but in my future work as a medievalist-in-training.  In fact, I think that using Mirador would be a good exercise whenever I engage in an essay or project in which I need to closely-look (which should be almost any visually-centered endeavor).  Through the very act of having to make decisions on what you mention (or do not mention) in annotations, one is forced to engage with the text and image in a more active manner.  Using Mirador, in conjunction with viewing the &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; manuscript (if one can), can help us as medievalists not only track and utilize our obversations later on, but also help us to question why we make certain distinctions (or not) and why these may—or may not—be important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, I add my thoughts on using T-PEN for online transcription. Prior to my using this program, I had done all annotations by hand. T-PEN not only (usually) sped up the process, but it also allowed me to more easily look up abbreviations on the fly.  In this, I appreciated the Latin dictionary linked to the transcription bar.  T-PEN also has excellent zoom-in features and tracking allowing you to clearly see where it is that you’re transcribing on the page (and how much you have left!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite features of T-PEN is the comment feature, allowing you to add a note which appears below your transcription.  I appreciated that I could do this as I went along line-by-line, rather than waiting at the end.  The only thing that could have made this more user-friendly, however, would be to not only note but highlight…allowing one to more clearly point out what letterform or feature of the MS line they were commenting on.  Maybe, though, this falls more along the lines of annotation and thus is better done on Mirador.  (Ben could answer this better, though, since he knows Mirador inside out!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these elements made T-PEN good to use, I have been struggling for a while with some bugs in the program.  For example, many &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; times I would go back lines in my transcription (using the “previous line” feature), only to then go back to my original place (using “enter” multiple times) and find that it had grouped together lines of my text again and again.  I found this immensely frustrating!  Perhaps there is a solution to this, but I have tried to look up other users comments on T-PEN, and haven’t yet found an answer to it.  Unfortunately, this colored my appreciation of T-PEN, but I hope to figure out a way for this not to happen in the coming week(s). Overall, it speeds up the process of transcription and is quite enjoyable to use…making one feel quite productive at the end, when you see all the hard, densely-abbreviated lines you’ve ably (or not-so-ably) transcribed!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/24/Christinablogpost2</link>
                <guid>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/24/Christinablogpost2</guid>
                <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>DLCL122-2016 - Christina&#39;s Discussion Questions, Week 4</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Week 4 Discussion Questions (continued from Week 3’s, which mention our other readings)–Transcription
&lt;em&gt;Note: this deals with Middle English transcriptions, not Latin. Are there slightly different things we have to consider when transcribing Latin/languages that are *not&lt;/em&gt; in English? (This also leads to the question if T-PEN is meant mostly for OE/ME and Latin; It seems to be this way considering the “Latin dictionary” tool at the bottom of the transcription window and the fact that there are shortcuts for thorn, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.) Is there a way that we can distinguish between transcribing glosses versues transcribing main text?  Perhaps this will become more clear to me as we use T-PEN in the following weeks.
2.) How much do we describe letterforms and scribal hand when we transcribe? (cf. rubrication; making mention of a particuarly interesting abbreviation/macron before we expand it; explaining the particular characteristics of a series of serifs–those “lozenge-shaped decorative finishes”)? I assume this would go into what T-PEN calls the “notes” section. The main caveat, however, that I can think of is that we wouldn’t want the notes to come up in the same window as the pure transcription–for that could distract from the main body of the text proper.  Is there a way to ‘hide’ the “notes” feature in T-PEN? (Again, this may be an obvious question, but as someone new to using T-PEN this is on my mind!).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <link>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/24/week4discussionquestions</link>
                <guid>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/24/week4discussionquestions</guid>
                <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>DLCL122-2016 - Liz&#39;s Discussion Questions, Week 4</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;discussion-questions-week-4&quot;&gt;Discussion Questions, Week 4&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;##Monday
* How does (or should) transcription handle non-textual elements of a page (filled intertextual space or illustrations, for example)? Should it address these at all?
* How do we transcribe abbreviations for which we do not know the expansion?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wednesday&quot;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No questions for today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/24/lizdiscussion-w4</link>
                <guid>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/24/lizdiscussion-w4</guid>
                <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>DLCL122-2016 - Liz&#39;s Blog Post, Exercise 2</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;exercise-2-annotating&quot;&gt;Exercise 2: Annotating&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently my interests have turned toward marginalia in manuscripts and early print books. Writing and drawing in the margins keeps books alive, show active participation in the text by humans. I am interested in who writes what, and where. Is most marginal writing part of the text, written by the scribe? Do readers tend to write more in the outer or lower margins? When readers are writing, is it more often than not related to the text they are reading?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin exploring these questions, I browsed thorugh Stanford’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://exhibits.stanford.edu/mss/browse/browse-all&quot;&gt;digitized manuscript collection&lt;/a&gt;. Early on it became clear that legibility and my own paleographical experience would be a limiting factor, as often I found marginalia unreadable. I selected 10 items which appeared to have the most legible and interesting marginalia at a cursory glance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My original plan was to use Mirador to tag instances of marginalia (and only tag– the only written description I might want would be a transcription of the marginalia, which will come in a later exercise), based on categorizations I encountered while reading Stephen Orgel’s &lt;em&gt;The Reader in the Book&lt;/em&gt;, plus a few of my own. These categories were active reading (a reader leaving comments on a text), correction (a scribe or reader correcting the text), recording (making note of something unrelated to the text, such as a business transaction), structural (text/symbols that are part of the structure of the text, such as section numbering), and illustration (doodles, maniculae, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Satisfied with the coverage of my categories, I set off to tag. Right away I found it quite difficult to fit what I was seeing on the page into the categories, not because the categories were insufficient but because, as previously feared, my ability to read the text was limiting progress. While I had done well to choose the most legible examples I could find in the collection, making out characters was still a challenge, and my minimal knowledge of Latin was doing me no favors. Structural elements and illustration were easy to pick out, but corrections, recordings, and active reading I found near indistinguishable. Without writing out a full transcription of everything I found, I was getting nowhere fast. Since transcription is to be done in the coming weeks, I changed my strategy. Rather than tagging based on my original categories, I tagged (and re-tagged) based on whether the marginalia appeared to be scribal or non-scribal. This, too, was not as easy as it might be for someone with more paleographic experience; I am satisfied that what I have is &lt;em&gt;close enough&lt;/em&gt; for this initial step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outcome of this exerise is not quite what I desired before starting, but I have been able to make a couple of observations so far. First, that most of the marginal writing in these items appears to be non-scribal. This is in line with what I would have predicted– I would assume that more often than not if a scribe had something to say or correct, it would be in the body of the text. Second, what I did not expect to see (or did not think to expect) is that scribal writing appears more frequenty in the left and right margins, and is less likely to be written in a way that is not in line with the appearance of the page (upside down, or sideways, for example). After transcription I hope to be able to explore the reasons behind these observations, and inch closer to my original categorization scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/23/lizblog2</link>
                <guid>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/23/lizblog2</guid>
                <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>DLCL122-2016 - Christina&#39;s Discussion Questions, Week 3</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;week-3-discussion-questions&quot;&gt;Week 3 discussion questions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Clemens and Graham’s chapter on correction, glossing, and annotation talks about the scribal tools and techniques involved in the “nitty-gritty” elements of manuscript production. As someone new to digital renditions of manuscripts (having transcribed them solely by hand in the past) how do digital humanists usually account for erasures and re-writing over those marked-out areas?  If we believe a medieval scribe to have made the error of “eyeskip” (which C&amp;amp;G define as omitting the same word, phrase, or sequence of letters that appear twice in close succession) how can we make note of this in our digital annotation?&lt;br /&gt;
—-And now a question of glossing: do we treat the location of where certain glosses are (cf. glossae collectae–those fully separate from the text itself; interlinear glosses; glosses in the main text) and what type they are (lexical/synonym vs. suppletive/omissions) &lt;em&gt;differently&lt;/em&gt; when we go into annotating them digitally?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Digital Mappaemundi (Maps of the World) disusses the use of digital ‘layers,’ whereby “different research questions involving a single image may be addressed separately through annotation (also allowing one to choose precisely how &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; layers they would like to view at one time). This seems to present a solution to our frustration with the BL’s excess of metadata in lengthy, sometimes-bordering-upon-impenetrable, paragraphs. How common are digital layers in literary manuscripts?  As its name suggests, the Mappaemundi project focuses on maps mostly.
—-Think more about: Geospatial bias and how it can relate to literary/biblical/philosophical texts too? (cf. C&amp;amp;G’s term “archaeology of the book” and idea of the book as a space)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/20/week3discussionquestions</link>
                <guid>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/20/week3discussionquestions</guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>DLCL122-2016 - Liz&#39;s Discussion Questions, Week 3</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;discussion-questions-week-3&quot;&gt;Discussion Questions, Week 3&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;##Monday
No class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wednesday&quot;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the reading on Digital Mappaemundi the authors mentioned features of plans for features that addressed each of the scholarly primitives we have discussed previously. I’ve noticed a trend, between the Mirador Github issues, this reading, and technology generally  toward expecting one platform/application to address all our needs– is this desirable?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is it defeatist to say there are problems that aren’t worth trying to solve, at least until there is a complete overhaul of the current approach? When is it okay to give up on a project?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What can physical annotation do that the tools we’ve seen so far does not replicate sufficiently? Are these tools still working to replace physical annotation, or strictly building on it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/20/liz-discussion-w3</link>
                <guid>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/20/liz-discussion-w3</guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>DLCL122-2016 - Christina&#39;s Discussion Questions, Week 2, part 2</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;week-2-discussion-questions-christina&quot;&gt;Week 2 discussion questions (Christina)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the words of Hilmo, “Medieval reading often included looking, in a non-linear, holistic way, at all the components of the page.”  The overall theme of Hilmo’s essay is on the centrality of the visual—images—in the medieval mind.  Hilmo speaks of how images can, and should, be read as text (cf. the monastic practice of ruminatio, per Bede’s 8th-c. account of Caedmon), as something which requires unpacking and a peeling-back of layers.  How might this relate to our discussion of the tasks involved in annotation and transcription?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Moreover: To the medieval mind an image was an animative, performative presence to be decoded and ruminated upon (particularly with the rise of mendicant orders).  This usually involved having a ‘toolkit’ of symbolism and connections at the ready. How might we, as modern viewers, recreate this ‘toolkit’ of connections through our digital presenting of manuscripts?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do we need to take into account the basic genre of a manuscript (sacred, secular, somewhere-in-between) when creating a digital tool for studying it?  In other words, Hilmo’s essay deals with manuscripts containing visual images–something usually restricted to the domain of art historians.  How might the technologies we produce for medieval objects (the codex, in particular) tread the line between being produced for scholars of text versus scholars of image? (The text v. image comparison is one made frequently in medieval studies–whereby text becomes image, and image becomes text).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An aside: Has there been a digital survey of iconophobic evidence in western manuscripts (British, Carolingian…and Byzantine, if we head into eastern MSs)?  Ie: smudgings out of eyes, etc.  I began to think along these terms because a) it’s the topic of my thesis and b) Hilmo’s essay begins with, essentially, a brief survey of western (and some eastern–Byzantium, Islamic) concern over the ‘power’ invested in images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/13/week2discussionquestions</link>
                <guid>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/13/week2discussionquestions</guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>DLCL122-2016 - Christina&#39;s Discussion Questions, Week 2</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;week2-discussion-questions&quot;&gt;Week2 discussion questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The first question deals with how we decide upon our digital priorities: Unsworth says that while we can create all the software we want, but without it being “developed and tested in the context of real scholarly use” it can be useless.  Furthermore, he warns against “customization, because purpose-built or project-centered software is unlikely to provide broad support for functional primitives.”  This claim makes sense, yet how is it best put to action in the ‘real-world’?  For example, does every scholar working on Blake manuscripts (which Unsworth makes mention of in his talk on Inote) need to have a process by which they ‘try out’ a specific digital archive, so we can have as large a sample set of scholars as we can, trying out certain software?  This got me to thinking about the nature of the digital humanities.  It seems we often make software, or rework an old online repository, to fulfill a specific need—or to advance a certain university’s (or professor’s) specific project.  But what happens to other material that won’t be touched, or that doesn’t garner the digital attention that other material gets?  I understand that we must start somewhere—and that somewhere is better than nowhere—but how do we determine our priorities in digitizing and creating new software?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To quote O’Donnell, “Technology ages faster than information.”  O’Donnell gives a fairly balanced perspective on the positives and negatives of digital scholarship in the medieval realm.  One of his most interesting examples, the Electronic Domesday Book—initiated by the BBC—turned out to be a catastrophic failure.  It was not only too expensive for its target audience and was also designed for certain computers only, both elements that condemned it to its own obsolescence.  This is a rather large question to tackle, but how can we work to make sure we don’t produce ‘failures’ of this sort, schemes where vast quantities of time, energy, and money seem to be wasted in the end?  O’Donnell’s overall impression of Wikipedia seems quite positive, illumining his opinion that collaboration is the key to solving many of these problems.  Do repositories and databases, then, need to have a way in which users can collaborate and edit—like Wikipedia?  What do we sacrifice with regards to accuracy and legitimacy when doing so?  Is it worth it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/11/week2christinaquestions</link>
                <guid>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/11/week2christinaquestions</guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>DLCL122-2016 - Liz&#39;s Blog Post, Exercise 1</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;exercise-1-discovering&quot;&gt;Exercise 1: Discovering&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this exercise, I examined both the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/Default.aspx&quot;&gt;British Library’s digitized manuscripts viewer&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wamcp.bibalex.org/&quot;&gt;Wellcome Arabic Manuscripts Online&lt;/a&gt;. As a part-time computer scientist, the user interface of each repository is what grabbed my attention– let’s begin with a brief overview of the features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;british-library&quot;&gt;British Library&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manuscripts can be searched for by keyword, date range, shelfmark, title, author or scribe, provenance, and/or bibliography. Searching returns a thumbnail, shelfmark, date, and brief description for every manuscript found, and the results sortable by shelfmark, author, title, or date (interestingly, not sortable by all the potential search parameters). Alternatively, manuscripts can be browsed by shelfmark, author, scribe, or title. When browsing, the user is presented with a list of every manuscript, sorted by the selected field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once choosing a particular manuscript, search and browse both put you to that manuscript’s description page. This page offers the expected metadata, when available: shelfmark, content description, dates, a thumbnail image, language, location, author, title, provenance, a bibliography. For many manuscripts, much of this information is missing– either unknown or simply not supplied (in the case of a content or physical description).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clicking on the thumbnail leads to the image viewer. This is one area that leaves much to be desired. The controls to navigate through the manuscript are placed at the top right, while a different set of controls to manipulate the current image (limited to full screen and zoom) are located lower on the left. There is some sort of page header without a clear function, and only one object can be viewed at a time (leaving it to the intrepid user to open multiple browser windows themselves).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wellcome-arabic-manuscripts-online&quot;&gt;Wellcome Arabic Manuscripts Online&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wellcome website is, from the start, much less welcoming than the British Library site. The design looks quite clunky and dated. It also presents a search tool on the homepage, but the functionality is hit or miss. Manuscripts in the browse view can be filtered by approximate date, librarian date, scribal date, decorations, and language; they can be browsed by shelfmark, author, title, colophon, tahmid, scribe, and mistra height. The distinction between a search-like way of finding a text and browsing a bit fuzzy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On selecting a particular manuscript, both the metadata for that object and the image viewer are presented, side-by-side. Metadata is tabbed into a summary, content description, physical description, and history. The viewer displays thumbnail navigation on the side, and a scrolling-view of the larger images in the main portion of the window. It also offers the option to download the current image in a variety of formats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crucially, the Wellcome experience stands out in its ability to display two different objects side-by-side in a single window. After viewing one manuscript, all other manuscripts in the search or browse results will display a button which says “Compare with &lt;first manuscript=&quot;&quot;&gt;&quot;. This shows two instances of the viewer, with the manuscript metadata pushed below.&lt;/first&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reflection&quot;&gt;Reflection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When desiging a tool, a  major concer of the developers must be their audience. Who is using the tool should dictate which features are implemented and how simple, or complecated, the user is allowed to make their experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would think the target audience of the British Library’s digital collection would be a less scholarly, more “general public” audience (the casual user) than most repositories. They are, afterall, a big institution with a big, recognizable name. The user experience, however, seems to contradict that. The interface is much cleaner than that of the Wellcome collection, for sure, but the steps of getting to the actual viewing of an object might intimidate a casual user. Searching and browsing are straight forward enough. Once on a manuscript description page, though, trouble starts. The more famous manuscripts, especially those highlighted on the home page are more likely to be viewed by a casual user. Those are also precicely the manuscripts for which the description is monstrously intimidating. Impenetrable walls of text describing every detail of the object are not inviting to a casual user. If they do make it past that to the viewer, it feels odd and dated, with less than desirable controls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wellcome collection, on the other hand, I would not expect to be friendly to those not versed in the subject. It is a very particular set of manuscripts, all Arabic texts dealing with health and medicine, not exactly the sort of thing a casual user would seek out. The target audience is very specifically scholars interested in Arabic manuscripts about medicine, so it is fair of the design to assume a knowledgable audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or is it? When a tool is made publiclly available on the internet, there is no telling who will be using it. The target audience in mind during development may turn out not to be the audience reached, at all. In the case of the British Library, they may very well have intended for the experience to be pleasant for the general public as well as scholars. Whether or not they succeeded is very subjective, but it does not seem unreasonable to claim they are losing part of that audience with intimidating presentation of information. With Wellcome, they may have only had a small audience in mind, but their manuscript information and image representation is quite friendly and usable for a broader audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is entirely a question of interface design, but it has an impact on how readily people can discover and use texts (or anything) from online repositories. It is my (admittedly untested) opinion that there is always happy medium between functionality and friendliness. The perfect example, from these two repositories, is the difference in handling of metadata. Both supply the same information, but Wellcome hides much of it upfront, sparing a casual visitor from information they don’t care to see, while still allowing easy access to that information for those who &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; want to see it. A tool can be full-featured &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; simple to use, if you keep in mind that you have no gaurantees of your audience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/11/lizblog1</link>
                <guid>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/11/lizblog1</guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>DLCL122-2016 - Christina&#39;s Blog Post 1</title>
                <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;blog-post-1-taken-from-practical-exercise-1&quot;&gt;Blog Post 1 (taken from Practical Exercise 1)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;christina-smith&quot;&gt;Christina Smith&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content, metadata, additional information, one’s ability to interact with the resources&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week’s blog post focuses upon two online digital repositories: the British Library’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/&quot;&gt;Digitised Manuscripts Home&lt;/a&gt; and the Bodleian Library’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bodley.ox.ac.uk/dept/scwmss/wmss/online/medieval/index.html#manuscript&quot;&gt;Electronic Catalogue of Medieval &amp;amp; Renaissance Manuscripts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I initially chose these two because, for the (as of yet) non-digital medievalist in me, they seemed quite opposite in appearance and functionality.  It was after looking into the Bodleian’s Electronic Catalogue of Medieval &amp;amp; Renaissance Manuscripts more that I figured out that it serves as a catalogue—and a somewhat rudimentary one at that, rather than a full-fledged, interactive site (evident if one but compare this electronic catalogue with the Bodleian’s main site).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the beginning, it is evident that the British Library’s Digitised Manuscripts Home caters to a different audience than that of the Bodleian’s Electronic Catalogue of Medieval &amp;amp; Renaissance Manuscripts.  The content given on the Bodleian’s catalogue is sparse, its “conventions” laid out in a teal box at the beginning.  Obviously, the site gears towards a user who knows precisely what she is looking for—preferably the manuscript’s shelfmark (since that is the easiest way to search this site).  Clicking on any one of the “Manuscript Collections” is useful inasmuch as it takes you to a simple list of manuscripts with their respective metadata and a few digitized images, if one is lucky.   For example, MS. Barocci 1—the first manuscript listed under the MSS. Barocci collection of Greek manuscripts—has only images from the catalogue (in print form) and quarto.  There are few, if any, images from the folios themselves (for example, MS. Barocci 3), not permitting the user any ability to visually compare across manuscripts.  The metadata is sparse, presented in one strip, and lacking the latest bibliography.  Most bibliographic material dates to the early 1990’s, showing that this site was likely last updated at that time.  Obviously, there’s much scholarly work that’s been done since then!  When one clicks upon the folios, they are poorly scanned and one can’t zoom in or use toolbars as is possible on the British Library site, showing that the site is designed for quick usage, perhaps only useful for acquiring date, language, and shelfmark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In comparison, the British Library’s Digitised Manuscripts Home appeals to a wider, even non-academic audience.  Clearly, this is in line with the British Library’s mission statement as a whole (similar to the British Museum)—that idea that its physical library in London is a museum for the world, a place where visitors can merely ‘stop in’ to view some of Britain’s greatest wonders.  The “Highlights” tab is visually appealing (located on the right hand side of the opening page), admittedly drawing one’s attention to the ‘big hits’ held by the Library—sometimes dangerously eclipsing lesser-known, but equally as important, manuscripts and items.  The “Search” feature on the opening page is most useful for its “Keyword” feature.  The “Date” slider is partially useful.  It certainly looks good—inviting for the casual user—but the functionality payoff is not as great as one would hope.  For one, there’s no information prior to 0CE, and it is also prone to stalling (at least one Macs) because of the large swathe of material it draws from.  In fact, for the casual viewer (even academic, perhaps), it would be more useful to search by region of the world, or to have an interactive date bar in which certain manuscripts were located along a continuum, allowing for immediate visual interaction with the material.  (Perhaps this is the art historically-trained part of me talking now!).  As befitting a major national repository, the British Library’s metadata for a given manuscript is extensive indeed—its content almost a bit too overwhelming.  One can’t isolate one piece of information from another, meaning that she is forced to look at the entire swathe of metadata in one fell swoop.  This includes date, title, content, binding (if possible to view), language, physical description, ownership, and bibliography.  The bibliography of the British Library’s online site—even for lesser-known acquisitions—is impressive indeed.  Perhaps this is a function of the Library’s active connections with current scholars in the field (such as Michelle P. Brown, who both worked and published for/at the British Library), but it also illumines the Library’s emphasis on the spreading of information out into the greater world of advanced, and more casual, learning.  When clicking upon a digital folio, so as to enlarge it, there is an irritating drop-down pane which appears with detail on the content of the manuscript.  It’s an abbreviated version of the extensive metadata on the previous page.  This serves more as a distraction than anything else, particularly when all one wants to do is to go to the navigation panel slightly below this drop-down pane.  (You also can’t click on the red “British Library” banner to go back to the home page—another irritating feature!).  In all, while the British Library’s website is more “glitzy” and aesthetically pleasing, it fails in some crucial components—from these small features to the fact that you can’t easily compare manuscript images with other manuscript images, save from opening new windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Digital Bodleian Library, obviously a much newer online repository than its Electronic Catalogue of Medieval &amp;amp; Renaissance Manuscripts from the 1990’s, opens with images of the binding of a given manuscript.  One chooses between the manuscripts they want from among other ones, located in boxes side-by-side.  This layout is inviting, emphasizing the visual nature of the holdings—something which I mentioned above as being important when we try to recreate objects that necessarily derive meaning from their tactility and functionality as book.  The metadata is wisely included on the side, not taking away from the visual aspect of the page and its scribal hand.  A negative, though, would be that the folios are preserved as single-sheets, rather than as bifolia.  This doesn’t allow the viewer to have the experience of page turning recreated before them.  Nor does it permit the viewer to truly see interactions across the page, across the gutter—something crucial to any study of medieval manuscripts.  I need to think more about this element as I look through more digital repositories—something I haven’t spent much time doing before this class, as I’ve worked more on non-codex archaeological objects.  The Digital Bodleian Library, however, overall seems to be a good compromise between the sparse, almost counter-useful layout of the Electronic Catalogue of Medieval &amp;amp; Renaissance Manuscripts and the overwhelming, somewhat unhelpful structure of the BL’s Digitised Manuscripts Home.  The metadata of the Digital Bodleian Library does not obstruct one from viewing the codex itself, and the navigation is visually appealing and, on the whole, relatively ‘easy’ to use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/11/BlogPost1</link>
                <guid>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/11/BlogPost1</guid>
                <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>DLCL122-2016 - Liz&#39;s Discussion Questions, Week 2</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;discussion-questions-week-2&quot;&gt;Discussion Questions, Week 2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;«««&amp;lt; HEAD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;monday&quot;&gt;Monday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=======
##Monday
»»»&amp;gt; liz-fischer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Unsworth gives 7 “scholarly primatives”:  Discovering, Annotating, Comparing, Referring, Sampling, Illustrating, and Representing. Discovering, annotating, comparing, referring, and sampling are intuitive enough, but what is the difference between illustrating and representing in this context?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“information that is for all intents and purposes lost… [content] produced using computers or operating systems that ultimately lost out to more popular competitors” This line in the O’Donnell reading got me thinking– are we on our way to a more stable technological situation, or is standardization a false sense of security?&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What exactly is meant by “unnegotiated interactions”? He says, “Developers produce content assuming users will be able to process it; users access content assuming it will be suitable for use with their processors.” Is this just another way of talking about standarization?
«««&amp;lt; HEAD
=======&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wednesday&quot;&gt;Wednesday&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While reading Hilmo, I found myself thinking more about the act of reading about images than about what was actually being said. Of course not every point can be made by simply showing the image in question; how might we, if we were to produce a new version of this reading in a digital format, improve on the experience?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mirador idea: ability to link annotations to one another.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is not, strictly speaking, a question; it is just something I noticed and would like to discuss.
Taking a page straight from Unsworth’s examples of primitives, I present the following passage from Hilmo, and a deformation of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;| Text with Image      |  Image with Text  | 
|:————-:|:————-:|
|The visual adds to, complements, and sometimes changes the verbal text; it rarely literally reproduces it. Images placed before a text create certain kinds of expectaion and anticipation, while those placed at the end can be particularly important in determining what the reader is to take away from the reading experience.”|The verbal adds to, complements, and sometimes changes the image; it rarely literally reproduces it. Text placed before an image creates certain kinds of expectaion and anticipation, while that placed at the end can be particularly important in determining what the viewer is to take away from the viewing experience.”|
»»»&amp;gt; liz-fischer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/10/lizweek2questions</link>
                <guid>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/10/lizweek2questions</guid>
                <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>DLCL122-2016 - Discussion Questions Week 1</title>
                <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;discussion-questions-for-the-readings-for-week-1&quot;&gt;Discussion questions for the readings for Week 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Raymond Clemens and Timothy Graham, “Manuscript Description,” in &lt;em&gt;Introduction to Manuscript Studies&lt;/em&gt;, pp. 129-134.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;http://toolingup.stanford.edu/?page_id=123&quot;&gt;Digitization&lt;/a&gt;” in &lt;em&gt;Tooling Up for Digital Humanities&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Richard Gartner, Lou Burnard, and Peter Kidd, “&lt;a href=&quot;http://cds.library.brown.edu/conferences/tei10/tei10.papers/gartner.html&quot;&gt;A TEI extension for the description of medieval manuscripts&lt;/a&gt;”, 2003.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elaine Treharne, Suzanne Paul, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5ApccnEawfs&quot;&gt;Shelf  marks and catalogs&lt;/a&gt;,” 2015. (video)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;liz-fischer&quot;&gt;Liz Fischer:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Clemens and Graham reading gives a very extensive list of things that should be included in a catalog description. Supposing one has limited resources for a cataloging effort, what falls (or should fall) by the wayside? At what level of lack-of-detail does a description become useless?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What happens to descriptions when information can’t be found? How does this affect digital cataloging, specifically?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Related to both of the above: with online cataloging, to what extent can you rely on knowing your audience?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the section of Digitization that discussed TEI, the following was written:
&amp;gt; “Many initiatives such as Google Books are attempting to automate the process in order to enhance millions of digitized sources. This leads to its own set of problems, as subtle distinctions can be lost. As Worthey says, “It’s dangerous for a humanities scholar to entrust too much to a programmer or mathematician.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do we balance maintaining subtlety with making the most of digital tools? How might this “loss of subtlety” make us rethink what is important to know?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;christina-smith&quot;&gt;Christina Smith:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A somewhat broad question: If, according to Clemens and Graham, the work of a paleographer depends upon careful attention to the physical characteristics of a folio, how might we–as makers and users of digital technology–simulate the workings of a real page?  Here I note attempts at using a “page flipping” feature.  This also got me to thinking about the need for a repository to have a “full size” button which allows one to view the full size of the manuscript on the screen, even if it covers more than what the screen can see in one fell swoop (rather than ‘full size’ which usually just blows up the manuscript to the dimensions of the computer screen, without thought to the differing sizes in manuscripts which can tell us a lot about production and use).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A more specific question: In Elaine Treharne and Suzanne Paul’s video on shelf marks, Suzanne mentions that shelf marks are, themselves, a medieval invention.  How might we digitally represent where a medieval book was kept on its shelf (or, does this even do anything productive)?  Suzanne also mentions that one must often try to search for misspellings of names/collections (ie: Cotton Nero, etc.) in order to find as much information as they can find on a given manuscript.  Otherwise, she says, large quantities of information/resources can be left out.  How might our technologies accommodate these misspellings and correct spellings–all in one–so that a user can access as much material together at once?  (I’m not phrasing this well, but hopefully will be able to say it clearly in class tomorrow).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/06/dlcl122_discussion1</link>
                <guid>http://blalbrit.github.io/2016/01/06/dlcl122_discussion1</guid>
                <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        </item>


</channel>
</rss>
